Guide to the Anthony Mulvey-Reyes Collection of New York City LGBTQ+ Ephemera 1991-1999 PM 1
New-York Historical Society
Anthony Mulvey-Reyes Collection of New York City LGBTQ+ Ephemera
1991-1999
New-York Historical Society
Mulvey-Reyes, Anthony
PM 1
.209 Linear feet in 1 half document box.
The Anthony Mulvey-Reyes Collection of New York City LGBTQ+ Ephemera is a collection of approximately 111 pieces of ephemera from LGBTQ+ events and nightlife from 1991-1999 in New York City, especially Manhattan. Collected by Anthony Mulvey-Reyes, a gay Latino man, the bulk of the collection consists of invitations, ads, posters, and flyers for LGBTQ+ nightlife parties at institutions such as The Limelight, Sound Factory, and Tunnel.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by material type and chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Anthony Louis Mulvey-Reyes was born in 1972 and grew up in the Gun Hill Road section of the Bronx. He started attending LGBTQ+ clubs and nightlife in New York City shortly afer he came out to his family as a gay man on Valentine's Day 1991. A year later in 1992, he co-founded the Neutral Zone, a LGBTQ+ youth center in a former restaurant on Christopher Street in the West Village. Mulvey-Reyes helped fundraise for the center and served as a site manager as well, where he worked the coat check, opened and closed the center, and cleaned. From 1993-1994, he worked as a receptionist at Bilange, Inc. a manufacturer of bath products which dissolved in 1997. Mulvey-Reyes then worked as a receptionist and phone operator at 227 East 56th Street, a building out of which a number of businesses that catered to or were owned by LGBTQ+ people operated. Many of these businesses were investments of Robert DeBenedictis, a New York City businessman who had bought 227 East 56th Street in 1981 after first opening the East Side Club, a 24-hour bath house, on parts of three of the building's floors in 1976. Working at 227 East 56th Street, Mulvey-Reyes made connections that subsequently allowed himm to take a job at the West Side Club, a 24-hour bath house opened in 1994 by DeBenedictis. Mulvey-Reyes worked there from 1995-1996 where he managed the front desk, checked wallets, took people to their rooms, and provided towels. In 1996-1997, he then worked at Caswell-Massey, the oldest fragrance and personal care product company in America, as an assistant manager and salesman in their flagship store on Lexington Avenue at 48th Street. He came to work at the New-York Historical Society in 1998. As of 2023, Mulvey-Reyes is a Senior Sales Associate at the New-York Historical Society Museum Store.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to all qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Anthony-Mulvey Reyes, February 1, 2023.
Scope and Contents
This collection, assembled by Anthony Mulvey-Reyes, includes programs, invitations, advertising cards, mailers, posters, newsletters, magazines, pamphlets, booklets, membership cards, club kid trading cards, and tickets from various LGBTQ+ events and nightlife across New York City, especially Manhattan, in the 1990s. The institutions represented include boybar, Crowbar, Limelight, The Men's Room at Webster Hall, Palladium, Roxy, Sound Factory, Tilt, and Tunnel as well as advertisements for the Columbia Gay and Lesbian Dances. Many of these events highlighted in the material feature Marc Berkely, a New York City club promoter and co-founder of HX magazine, and Junior Vasquez, an American DJ and record producer, as well as John Blair, the former owner of several notable New York City LGBTQ+ clubs and current owner of The Out NYC in Hell's Kitchen. The contents include BANG booklets no. 1-4 and no. 6, which feature ads and invitations to LGBTQ+ events and nightlife throughout New York City in late 1991 and early 1992. Additionally, there are three programs from balls and house functions in the 1990s. Also of note is a folded poster for the 1992 Gay and Lesbian Pride and History Month, on which LGBTQ+ people in government are featured as well as a calendar of Pride events for June 1992.
The ephemera captures some of the events in 1990s held by renowned New York City LGBTQ+ nightlife institutions at a time when such nightlife was often under scrutiny by the city government. As a result, this material provides glimpses into some of these nightlife institutions and their figures, such as Studio 54, a disco nightclub that operated from 1977-1996 and featured performers such as RuPaul Charles, Gloria Gaynor, and others; and The Limelight, which first opened in November 1983 in the former Episcopal Church of the Holy Communion at 656-662 Avenue of the Americas at West 20th Street. LGBTQ+ clubs such as these and others were known in the 1990s for their wild themes (from underwear to Easter Bunny parties) and the presence of the Club Kids, a group of New York City dance club personalities known for their flamboyant costumes and big personalities that came to include people such as Amanda Lepore and Richie Rich, among others. This kind of nightlife, characterized by its exuberance and glamour, began to decline in 1994 as then mayor, Rudy Giuliani, announced a crackdown on Quality of Life Offenses, which targeted poor and marginalized communities in New York City. Additionally, the 1996 murder and dismemberment of Andre "Angel" Menendez, a well-known personality at The Limelight, by Michael Alig, a founding figure of the Club Kids, spelled the beginning of the end for the popualarity of this type of LGBTQ+ nightlife. In 1998, The Limelight finally closed after being repeatedly shut down by the police due to allegations of drugs and accusations against Peter Gatien, the owner of The Limelight as well as Club USA, Tunnel, and Palladium, of running a drug ring out of the club. This collections highlights this particular era of New York City LGBTQ+ nightlife with ads and invitations from parties at clubs such as Limelight and Sound Tunnel, membership cards that granted reduced fares at themed parties across New York City LGBTQ+ clubs, and pictures in magazines and newspapers of such nightlife.
Gay community -- New York (State) -- New York.; Gay pride celebrations -- New York (State) -- New York; Gays -- New York (State); Gays -- Social life and customs -- New York (State); Drag balls -- New York (State) -- New York; Nightlife -- New York (State) -- New York; Alig, Michael; Bank, Matthew; Beltram, Joey; Berkley, Marc, -2010; Blair, John E.; Boy Bar; Club USA; Columbia University; Dijon, Honey; Greenwich Village Youth Council's Neutral Zone; Homo Xtra (HX Magazine); Keoki; Knuckles, Frankie; Lady Bunny; Van Zandt, Lahoma; Limelight (Nightclub); Men's Room at Webster Hall; Out Magazine; Palladium (Nightclub); Project X Magazine; Roxy (Nightclub); Saint at Large, Inc.; Sound Factory (Nightclub); Studio 54 (Nightclub); Sutter, Beto; Tenaglia, Danny; Tunnel (Nightclub); Twilo (Nightclub)
- Ads and Invitations
  Scope and Contents
  This folder contains ads and invitations to events and nightlife at LGBTQ+ institutions across New York City from 1991-1999. Especially represented in the folder are ads for The Limelight and Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel.
  - Mea Culpa Celebrates the Opening of "IMAGO", May 3, 1991; May 10, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Blair Invites You to Roxy, July 13, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Hom-O-Sexual Snack-A-Teria" Lick It! at Limelight, September 4, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Winter Heat" Morning Party at Limelight, January 19, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Blair Invites You to Roxy, February 18, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Benefit for Treatment Action Guerillas" Lick It! At Limelight (2 copies), March 4 [1992] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lick It! Achievement Award for Queer Excellence: Presented to ChiChi LaRue, March 15, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Grand Opening" Res-Erection at Limelight (2 copies), April 3, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Don't Put All Your Men in One Basket Easter Party" Lick It! At Limelight (2 copies), April 15, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The First Anniversary" Lick It! at Limelight, May 13, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "blueboy" Lick It! At Limelight, May 20, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Outdoor Patio" Res-erection at Limelight, May 29, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Truth About Ecstasy" Forbidden Exchange at Palladium, June 4, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Trade Give Me Some" at Sound Factory Bar Grand Opening (2 copies), June 13, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gay Pride 1992 Power Rave at Tilt, June 28, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Out Magazine Presents Pride: A Deeper Love at Roxy, June 28, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Underwear Party" at the Sound Factory (2 copies), July 18, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Chip Duckett Presents Trade" at Sound Factory Bar, July 25 [1992] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Birthday Celebration for Mr. Junior Vasquez" at Sound Factory (2 copies), August 22, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sound Factory's First Annual Beige Party, November 28, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Basket Your Easter Bunny Never Delivered" The Men's Room at Webster Hall, April 11, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Blair Presents Merritt and Madonna at Roxy, April 17, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Blair Presents Saturdays at Roxy, December 31, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Blair Presents Saturdays at Roxy, February 18, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Dr. Dellinger's Twilo Tea" at Twilo, February 2 [1997] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Platinum New Year's Eve 1998 at Twilo, December 31, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel, February 7, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel, February 21, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Danny Tenaglia's Birthday Bash" Kurfew Saturday at Tunnel, March 7, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kurfew Presents "The Kurfew Easter Egg and Prize Hunt", April 18, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel, April 25, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "America's Largest Weekly Young Gay Dance Party" Kurfew Saturday, May 9, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "SeaSide Tanning" Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel, June 6, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "What are u doin' this Saturday nite?" Kurfew Saturdays at Tunnel, August 1, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - DRAMA! At Limelight, November 15, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Celebrating David Knapp's Birthday and Swan Lake on Broadway at Roxy, November 28, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kurfew 1999 at Tunnel, December 31, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - DRAMA! At Limelight, January 31, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Fierce Ultimate Friday Nite Dance Party (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Squirt Farm Fridays at Crowbar (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Second Annual Underwear Party" Lick It! at Limelight (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - boybar Invitations (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Dance 'Til It Hurts" at Limelight (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Homage to the Harlem Houses Fashion Show" Disco2000 at Limelight (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lick It! At Limelight Honors Jeff and Rick Stryker, September 25 [1991 or 1996?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lick It! At Limelight, August 28 [1991 or 1996?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chip Duckett's ABC at Irving Plaza (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - MorPlay and Roofie @ Meow Mix Crasta Yo's B-day Joint (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - NYQ Madonna's Boyz at Palladium, January 18 [1992 or 1997?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - HERO Invitation (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mea Culpa Invitation (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Club Kid Cards
  In this folder, there are six total "Klub Kids Kards" from the early 1990s. These cards were given out at various Limelight events, including Disco2000.
  - Chris Uh4eah! (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Heather S. Uh4eah! (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alice Uh4eah! (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lahoma Van Zandt Disco2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Schuck E! Disco2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Club Membership Cards
  This folder contains Anthony Mulvey-Reyes' membership cards for various LGBTQ+ clubs across New York City. Of note are the "Fag Tags" which provided a reduced-tarif access to several clubs and events.
  - Chelsea Boys at Limelight (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fag Tag, The front of this item consists of a black background with a turquoise heart and arrow in the middle. The latterin spells out in white "Fag Tag." (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fag Tag, This item is laminated and consists of a stone background with rainbow lettering spelling out "Fag Tag" on the front. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Blair's Twilo Saturdays (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Blair and Jason present Saturdays at Studio 54 VIP (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Junior Vasquez's Tunnel Card Tunnel After Hours Saturday (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Marc Berkley's Fag Tag, This item on the front features a black-and-white picture of a pectoral muscle and arm. The lettering spells out "This is Marc Berkley's Fag Tag" in green. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Marc Berkley's Fag Tag, This item is red and black. The features two men, one reclining with a book. On the back is a signature. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rome VIP (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Soda-Juice at Tunnel (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Twilo (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - This Is Your New Fag Tag (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Water at Limelight (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Columbia Gay and Lesbian Dances
  This folder contains invitations to gay and lesbian dances hosted at Columbia University.
  - 3rd Annual Columbia Pride Dance (2 copies), Friday June 26 [1993] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Black Party Columbia 3rd Saturday Dance (2 copies), Saturday March 21 [1992 or 1998?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Columbia 3rd Saturday Dance, Saturday April 20 [1991 or 1996?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Show Us Your Underwear" Columbia 3rd Saturday Dance, Saturday May 16 [1992 or 1998?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Columbia 3rd Saturday Dance, Saturday May 18 [1991 or 1996?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Columbia 3rd Saturday Dance, Saturday November 21 [1992 or 1998?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Folded Posters
  This folder contains folded posters from LGBTQ+ nightclubs in the 1990s, including Sound Factory posters highlighting members and The Saint at Large's "Black Parties." Additionally, there is a poster from June 1992 "Pride and History Month" with various LGBTQ+ government officials pictures and testimonies.
  - "Opening Night" The Men's Room at Webster Hall, October 18, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New York City June 92 Lesbian and Gay Pride and History, June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Saint at large Presents The Black Party Rites XVI, March 18, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Saint at large Presents Rites XVII The Black Party, March 16, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Manny" Sound Factory Membership Record (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Rob" Sound Factory Membership Record (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Magazines, Newspapers, and Pamphlets
  This folder contains various LGBTQ+ publications from the 1990s. BANG, distributed by The Limelight, advertises both fake and real events at its club ad highlights important nightlife figures and characters on the scene in the 1990s.
  - BANG Premier Issue Fall 1991, Wednesday November 13, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BANG Issue No. 2, November 18-December 20, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BANG Issue No. 3, December 11, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Safer Sex Keep It Up!" HomoXtra Volume 1, No. 14, December 12, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BANG Issue No. 4, December 18, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BANG Issue No. 6, January 1, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - OutYouth Newsmagazine for Young Lesbians, Bisexuals, and Gay Men Fall 1993 Issue No. 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Person to Person" The Village Voice, December 7-13, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - On the Wilde Side Volume 2, No. 5, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Knowing You" Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mailers
  This folder contains mail sent by LGBTQ+ nightlife and clubs sent to Anthony Mulvey-Reyes, including a mailer with the most recent iteration of the "Fag Tag."
  - 1993-1994 Fag Tag New Year's Parties, December 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership Application for Sound Factory Reopening, [1995] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Factory Experience Continues Junior Vasquez" at The New Tunnel, September 16, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous
  This folder contains two tickets and one letter. The letter comes from the executive director of the Greenwich Youth Village Council, John Pettinato.
  - Movie Ticket for Star Trek Genera, November 17, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Shampoo!" Foam Party at Irving Plaza Ticket, June 22, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter from John Pettinato to Anthony Mulvey-Reyes, July 6, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Programs
  In this folder are programs from events Anthony Mulvey-Reyes attending in the 1990s, including three programs for balls. Notably, there is a program for Paris Dupree's Paris Is Burning balls, from which the documentary of the name got its name.
  - Paris is Burning Part XVII at the Marc Ballroom, August 30, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pendavis L'Amour Ball at the Marc Ballroom, September 15, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Africa Ball at the Lincoln Square Neighborhood Center, Inc., November 24, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Hall June 1995 Program Schedule, June 22, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Ticket from the June 22, 1995 Gay Men's Chorus show tucked inside the program.